Patrick Bower

www.patrickbower.com bower.patrick@gmail.com Senior product designer working end-to-end on digital products. I bring a wealth of experience as both a practitioner and leader of design within product teams, with expertise that bridges UX, design, and engineering.

Skills

Design and UX

- Over 10 years dedicated to product design.
- Extensive UX methodologies.
- · Leading user research.
- · Advanced prototyping.
- · Conducting effective user testing.
- Creating and maintaining design systems.
- Understanding design technical limits.

Coding and Prototyping

- Five years as a dedicated front-end engineer.
- Thorough knowledge of JavaScript and React.
- · Proficient with web technology stacks.
- Solid understanding of coding best practices.
- Deep understanding of technical functions.
- Rapid and robust code prototyping.
- · Understanding of technical decision-making.

Leadership and Soft Skills

- Lead presentations and engage stakeholders.
- Facilitate engaging user workshops.
- Speak at conferences such as UX Brighton.
- Bridge deep design and technical discussions.
- · Collaborate with cross-functional teams.
- Lead the product process from end to end.
- · Mentor and manage team members.

Tools and Technologies

- · Advanced skills with Figma and Adobe.
- Remote techniques for research in Miro.
- Maximise productivity with AI tools.
- Dev frameworks, version control and CLIs.
- Strong Agile, Scrum, and Sprint practices.
- Gather insights with UserTesting and Hotjar.

Education

BA Visual Communication | Design

Birmingham UCE | 2001 - 2004

Achieved 2:1 with immediate work placement.

Experience

RAC | Lead Product Designer

Remote Contract | June 2023 - Sep 2024 (1 yr 3 mths)

Conducted a six-month redesign and replatforming of over 500 marketing pages. A strategic UX and design process resulted in a 9% average decrease in bounce rate, an 8% average increase in traffic, and a 3% increase in self-service channels, leading to a 1.5% reduction in call centre volume. Additionally, I led design projects for retention and acquisition, creating over 50 components to enhance a developing design system while establishing and documenting best practices.

DAZN | Senior Product Designer

London | Sep 2020 - May 2023 (2 yrs 8 mths)

Often working in cross-functional teams, I led the design of greenfield projects, including authentication across mobile, web, and living room platforms, to deliver account ownership globally to 15 million users in over 200 countries. I also took the initiative to create tools for high-fidelity interaction design, expediting user testing and engineering processes, and increasing release cycles by 10-20%.

Buildit | UX Engineer

London | Mar 2018 - Sep 2020 (2 yrs 6 mths)

While working with Fortune 500 companies, I led the design of new products for organisations such as Lloyds Bank, BP, and GSK. I also codeveloped a lean process package for cross-functional working, which increased sales leads by up to 30% for my department.

DD (acquired by EY) | Front End Engineer

London | Mar 2018 - Sep 2020 (2 yrs 6 mths)

Worked on projects for multinationals and start-ups, including creating a component library used by millions of users across global applications using React.js for Vodafone. I was chosen for European travel to deliver education and adoption across development hubs.

Freelance | Product Designer

London | Aug 2010 - Nov 2012 (2 yrs 3 mths)

Worked with clients including Firebrand, Glock, UAL, ASOS, and FIFA.

Boutique Agencies | Designer

London & Birmingham | Feb 2005 - Jul 2010 (5 yrs 5 mths)

Worked with clients including BBC, Universal, AEG and Fenchurch.